https://www.kilmorediocese.ie/diocesan-privacy-statement/

Diocesan Privacy Statement
Who we are:
The Diocese of Kilmore, Bishop’s House, Cullies, Cavan H12 P5W6
Telephone: 049 4331496
EMail: diocesansecretary@kilmorediocese.ie
The Diocese of Kilmore is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement & Privacy Policy explains our data processing practices and your options regarding the ways in which your personal data is used. This Privacy Statement & Privacy Policy is reflective of our compliance with Data Protection legislation in Ireland, to include the European GDPR and the Data Protection Acts 1988-2018.
Our Data Protection Officer
The Data Protection Officer for our Diocese can be contacted at dpo@elphindiocese.ie.
Data Protection Principles
We promise to follow the following data protection principles:
– Processing is lawful, fair, transparent. Our Processing activities have lawful grounds. We always consider your rights as a Data Subject before Processing Personal Data. We will provide you information regarding Processing upon request.
– Processing is limited to the purpose for which it was gathered.
– Processing is carried out using the minimum amount of Personal Data required for any purpose.
– We will not store your personal data for longer than needed.
– We will do our best to ensure the accuracy of data.
– We will do our best to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of data.
– We will use all reasonable means to avoid Breaches of Data. Where a Data Breach occurs, we will notify the relevant authority and follow their instructed next steps.
Data subject’s rights:
Those affected by this Privacy Statement & Privacy Policy have the following rights:
– Right to access: the right to request, access and copy of the personal information that we hold on you. We may charge a reasonable fee for 2 or more personal data requests. A single copy of personal data will be charged at no cost. Any access requests will need to be requested in writing or email. Evidence of identification will be required as this makes sure that the personal information is not given to the wrong person. Information will be sent within 1 month of receipt of the written request.
– Right to rectification: the right to have personal data rectified if it’s incorrect, out of date or incomplete.
– Right to be forgotten: the right to withdraw consent given to process data and the right to request that we delete personal data from our System (subject to compliance with any legal obligations or unless the data is required for any legal claims).
– The right to object how we use the personal data received (e.g. marketing purposes).
How we process your Personal Data
We will only process your Personal Data in line with the services provided on our website. This information may include your name, address, email address, phone number, etc. as provided by you for the provision of a service, e.g.:
· Signing up for a newsletter or event
· Signing up for volunteer or fundraising activities
· Signing up / making contact in relation to upcoming Pilgrimages
· Contacting us with a query in relation to information posted on our website
Any data processed on our behalf by contracted third party service providers, e.g. for the purpose of enhancing the services we provide to you will be bound by the same privacy standards. We will not disclose Personal Data to any other third parties unless we have consent to do so.
We will disclose Personal Data if it is believed in good faith that we are required to disclose it in order to comply with any applicable law, a summons, a search warrant, a court or regulatory order, or other statutory requirement.
You can choose to opt out of receiving information from us at any time by contacting the Diocesan Secretary at the contact details given above.
Cookies
“Cookies” are small pieces of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information from the browser. The Diocese of Kilmore website uses cookies to improve navigation and to enable traffic monitoring. Non-registered visitors of the site may be sent anonymous cookies to keep track of their browsing patterns and build up a demographic profile.
Whilst you do not need to allow your browser to accept cookies in order to browse much of our web site or to access many of our services, you must have cookies enabled if you wish to access any areas reserved for registered users. Most browsers allow you to turn off the cookie function. If you want to know how to do this please look at the help menu on your browser. As described above this will restrict the services you can use on our website.
How to contact the appropriate authority
Should you wish to report a complaint or if you feel that we have not addressed your concern in a satisfactory manner, you may contact:
Data Protection Commission,
21 Fitzwilliam Square South Dublin 2 D02 RD28 Ireland
+353 578 684 800, +353 761 104 800.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Statement & Privacy Policy.
Last update published July 2019.
The Bishop’s office
Bishop’s Secretary
Diocesan Pastoral Centre
Marriage Tribunal Office
Diocesan Safeguarding Office
Education Office
Diocesan Privacy Statement
Charities Regulatory Authority (CRA) Number: 20015084Revenue Charitable Status (CHY) Number:
7215
HomeBishop
Bishop’s Desk
Administration
Publications
Contact Us
DiocesePriests
Parishes
Accord Courses
©Copyright 2016 Diocese of Kilmore – Designed and Developed by Getonline Pro
We use cookies in our website to give you the most relevant experience by remembering your preferences and repeat visits. By clicking “Accept”, you consent to the use of the cookies explicitly. Visit Cookie Settings to know more about the cookies used on our website. Cookie PolicyNecessaryNon NecessaryUncategorizedAnalyticsPerformanceAdvertisementCookie settingsACCEPTPrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non Necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
Uncategorized
Undefined cookies are those that are being analyzed and have not been classified into a category as yet.
Analytics
Analytical cookies are used to understand how visitors interact with the website. These cookies help provide information on metrics the number of visitors, bounce rate, traffic source, etc.
Performance
Performance cookies are used to understand and analyze the key performance indexes of the website which helps in delivering a better user experience for the visitors.
Advertisement
Advertisement cookies are used to provide visitors with relevant ads and marketing campaigns. These cookies track visitors across websites and collect information to provide customized ads.
[ Placeholder content for popup link ]
WordPress Download Manager - Best Download Management Plugin
Close
